wealthyaffiliate.com 2019-07-09

# Privacy Policy - Wealthy Affiliate

## Wealthy Affiliate Privacy Policy

We take your privacy seriously and take measures to provide all users of the Wealthy Affiliate platform with a safe and secure environment. This starts with requiring only basic information to join our service, and the ability to use pseudonyms and usernames

When this policy mentions "we" or "us," it refers to the controller of your information under this policy. Your information is controlled by Wealthy Affiliate (Niche Marketing Inc.), Box 18 2354 Millstream Rd Victoria, BC, Canada V9B 6L2.

You should read this entire policy to learn more about how we handle privacy, data, and how we use any information that you provide. However, here are a few key points.

  * We require only basic information from you including name, email, and username to create an account with our service. You may use any information you wish, including pseudonyms if you would like to remain anonymous.

  * Any information entered into the system as a logged in member may be publicly visible or searchable including name, username, or content like questions, blog posts, training, public profile description, or comments.

  * Any personal information entered into the system can be updated and reviewed at any time from your account [settings page](https://my.wealthyaffiliate.com/home/my_profile) and public profile. You may change this information at any time, or (as of May 25th, 2018) disable your account entirely, removing all of your publicly visible content, and removing any personally identifiable information within our internal systems.

  * When you use Wealthy Affiliate, even if you're just browsing as a guest, we receive some information from you like the type of device you're using and your IP address.

## What Our Privacy Policy Covers

This policy covers how Wealthy Affiliate treats personal information that is collected and received, including information related to your use of Wealthy Affiliate products and internal services. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available.

This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, or to people that we do not employ or manage.

## Information Collected

Wealthy Affiliate collects personal information when you register, when you use our products or services, or when you visit our pages. When joining Wealthy Affiliate you are required to enter a name, email address, and username. This basic information is collected so that we can provide you with our services. Once registered and signed into our services, this information is available to us.

Wealthy Affiliate may collect information from your interactions with us, including publishing content in blog posts, questions, live chat, training, support, or any other area where you can enter and input content to the system. For example, when asking a question within the Wealthy Affiliate community, the information entered is stored so that we can display it back to you and the community.

We send notifications and communication via email and clicks are tracked to help us better understand our email communication platform. You have full control over what types of emails are received and this can be managed from your account settings page within your Wealthy Affiliate account, or accessed directly by clicking the management link in all emails that we send.

We automatically receive and record information in server logs from your browser, including your IP address, WealthyAffiliate.com cookie information, and the page you requested. The information in server logs is kept for a 60 day period in order to provide us with information to improve services and debug potential technical issues that may arise, protect against fraud, or malicious activity.

We provide control through the account settings to limit the data we collect from you and how we use it, as well as to control things like email communication, username displayed, name, or email used for logging in. This information is visible to you within your [account settings](https://my.wealthyaffiliate.com/home/my_profile) at anytime. It is not important to us to know your real identity. If you prefer to be anonymous then you can change your name, username, and email to anything that you like. Likewise on your public profile, you can choose to enter an image and add a description. Images and profile descriptions can be removed at any time by visiting your public profile at:

https://my.wealthyaffiliate.com/yourusername

Wealthy Affiliate is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Terms of Service](https://policies.google.com/terms) apply.

We use your information to fulfill your requests for products and services, improve our services, contact you, conduct research, and provide anonymous reporting. If you have questions about this policy, how we collect or process your personal data, or anything else related to our privacy practices, we would love to hear from you. You can contact us at any time.

<https://www.wealthyaffiliate.com/contact>

## Information Sharing

Some content at Wealthy Affiliate is public and is immediately visible and searchable by anyone in the world. Questions, blog posts, training, or comments may be indexed in search engines. You may communicate within WA under a pseudonym (username), and if you do not choose to use your real name this is completely fine. Your email address is not shared publicly.

Information that you enter as your name, username, and image may be shared within the Wealthy Affiliate community. For example, if you choose to upload an image of yourself, this image will be displayed within your profile and along side blog posts, questions, comments or other areas in the system.

We engage service providers to perform functions and provide services to us. For example, we use a variety of third-party services to help operate our services, such as keyword research, hosting and domain registrations, and to help us understand the use of our services. We may share your private personal data with such service providers subject to obligations consistent with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures, and on the condition that the third parties use your private personal data only on our behalf and pursuant to our instructions. Your payment information is forwarded to payment services providers to process payments; prevent, detect, and investigate fraud or other prohibited activities; facilitate dispute resolution such as chargebacks or refunds; and for other purposes associated with the acceptance of credit and debit cards.

In the event that Wealthy Affiliate is merged or acquired by another company, your information may be transferred to that entity. We will notify you before any information about you is transferred or of any changes to this privacy related to this process.

## Cookies

WealthyAffiliate.com may set and access WealthyAffiliate.com cookies on your computer. Cookies are used to keep you logged into our platform and to provide our system with the basic information to provide the services you are requesting. Cookies can be cleared at any time from your internet browser settings.

## Confidentiality and Security

We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may make changes to our Privacy Policy in the future, however, the most current version of the policy will govern our processing of your personal data and will always be available at the following URL: <https://www.wealthyaffiliate.com/privacy>. If we make a change to this policy that, in our sole discretion, is material, we will notify you by an update or email to the email address associated with your Wealthy Affiliate account. By continuing to access or use our services after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.
